hey guys this looks like a fun one we're
trying to find the area of the red
region if you want to try this on your
own pause it right now cuz I'm going to
solve it in 3 2 one so first step let's
copy it down and let's cut it in half
with the diagonal right here and let's
make all of this one region the entire
square is 10 * 10 which is 100 so that
makes this right here 50 and we don't
know the area of these so let's give
them a variable a and let's write an
equation for this right here we know
that the 2 A's plus this x + 50 is going
to equal the entire Square which is 100
and then we can subtract 50 from both
sides and also subtract 2 a from both
sides and that gives us X is equal to 50
- 2 a and this looks pretty important
let's put it up here so all we need to
do to solve for x is figure out the area
of these two A's and I've got a good
idea how to do that let's copy the
square again but let's only include the
top semicircle the area of that
semicircle is going to be P pi r 2 divid
2 and since the sides of the square are
10 the radius is going to be equal to
five so we can update this R to be 5
then 5^ 2 is 25 < * 25 / 2 is 12.5 piun
and next let's cut this with both
diagonals each of these triangles is 1/4
of the total square so this right
triangle up here is going to have an
area of 25 and then this piece right
here is literally the exact same thing
as this piece right here so it is also
equal to a and then this is the same
size is this so we'll call it a and now
we have another equation this 25 + 2 a
makes up the entire semicircle so it's
going to be equal to 12.5 pi and after
we subtract 25 from both sides we get 2
a is equal to 12.5 piun - 25 and now we
have a value for the 2A so let's solve
for x so now in the place of this 2A we
can plug in 12.5 piun - 25 this negative
is going to distribute to give us -2.5
piun and minus - 255 is + 25 next we can
combine like terms 50 + 25 is 75 and
this is still there and now we have the
area of the red region let's give it a
label of square units and put a box
around it and here's the approximate
value of 35.7 3 square units how
exciting